A. Lee McAlester Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
A. Lee McAlester Archives
1959-1975
IPAR.001023
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
10
The archives of A. Lee McAlester including mostly maps and photographs encompassing his career at Yale. These focus on his 1960 Yale dissertation, "Pelecypod faunas of the Late Devonian Chemung Stage, central New York."
McAlester, Arcie Lee
Biographical Sketch
Curater for Division of Inververtabrate Paleontology at the Yale Peabody Museum. 1959-1975. PhD from Yale University in 1960.
Description of the Material
Includes maps from his field areas, photographs of specimens, and miscellaneous other material (including his 1957 both biographic and collections related).
New York; Connecticut; Pennsylvania; Maine; USA; Maps; Photographs; Notebooks; Locality information; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Photographs, 1959-1975; Series I
  - Specimens. Photoghraphs of specimens. Specifically Bivalves., 1959-1975; 001027
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and negatives of Nuculoid bivalves Black and white negatives. ca 1960, 000615
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints of Devonian bivalves from New York; Dissertation. ca 1960, 000618
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and negatives of bivalves from Paquette Rapids Black and white prints and negatives, 1963; 000605
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and negatives of bivalves from Lake St. John Black and white prints and negatives, 1963; 000606
- Maps, 1959-1975; Series II
  - Maine. Topagraphic and Geological maps from Maine., 1959-1975; 001032
    - Geologic map. Fossil Locs. of Moose River Synclinorium, Maine (1: 62500). Boucot, A.J.: Geologic., 1961; 001944
    - Topographic map. Long Pond, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1924; 002279
    - Topographic map. Attean, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 002277
    - Topographic map. North East Carry, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 002281
    - Topographic map. Brassua Lake, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1957; 002278
    - Topographic map. Moose Head Lake, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1957; 002280
    - Topographic map. Pierce Pond, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1958; 002282
    - Topographic map. Spencer Lake, ME 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1958; 002283
  - Multiple States. Topographic and Geographic maps conatining more then one state., 1959-1975; 001033
    - Topographic map. Elmira, NY-PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1895; 001476
    - Topographic map. Waverly, NY-PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001540
    - Topographic map. Towanda, PA-NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1926; 001532
    - Topographic map. Susquehana, PA-NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1935; 001529
    - Topographic map. Sidney, NY-PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1943; 001525
    - Topographic map. Montrose, PA-NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001510
    - Topographic map. Caton, NY-PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001466
    - Topographic map. Elmira, NY-PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001477
    - Topographic map. Seeley Creek, NY-PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001524
    - Topographic map. Jackson Summit, PA-NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001497
    - Topographic map. Tioga, PA-NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001531
    - Topographic map. Waverly, NY-PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001541
    - Topographic map. Wellsburg, NY-PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001542
    - Topographic map. Wellsburg, NY-PA 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 002272
    - Topographic map. Millerton, NY-CT 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1955; 001507
  - New York. Topagraphic and geographic maps from New York., 1959-1975; 001030
    - Map. Portville, NY 7.5 (1: 24000), 002289
    - Topographic map. Durham, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1894; 001473
    - Topographic map. Oswego, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001513
    - Topographic map. Apalachin, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001450
    - Topographic map. Gilboa, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001482
    - Topographic map. Harford, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001489
    - Topographic map. Owego, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001515
    - Topographic map. Phoenicia, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001518
    - Topographic map. Norwich, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 002256
    - Topographic map. Hobart, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001492
    - Topographic map. Margaretville, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001504
    - Topographic map. Apalachin, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 002232
    - Topographic map. Greene, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 002243
    - Topographic map. Oxford, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 002260
    - Topographic map. Pitcher, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 002261
    - Topographic map. Nineveh, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1905; 002255
    - Topographic map. Angelica, NY 15.0 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1906; 002231
    - Topographic map. Delhi, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1911; 001470
    - Topographic map. Hartwick, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1912; 002247
    - Topographic map. New Berlin, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1912; 002254
    - Topographic map. Corning, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 625000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1914; 001468
    - Topographic map. Unadilla, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1918; 001537
    - Topographic map. Oneonta, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1918; 002258
    - Topographic map. Unadilla, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1918; 002270
    - Topographic map. Andes, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1922; 001449
    - Topographic map. Ellicottville, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1924; 002241
    - Topographic map. Belmont, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 002233
    - Topographic map. Walton, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 002271
    - Topographic map. Deposit, NY 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1926; 002240
    - Topographic map. Binghamton West, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1935; 001459
    - Topographic map. Binghamton East, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1937; 001458
    - Topographic map. Castle Creek, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1942; 001465
    - Topographic map. Chenango Forks, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1942; 001467
    - Topographic map. Binghamton East, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1942; 002234
    - Topographic map. Binghamton West, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1942; 002235
    - Topographic map. Castle Creek, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1942; 002236
    - Topographic map. Chenango Forks, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1942; 002237
    - Topographic map. Bloomville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1943; 001460
    - Topographic map. Delhi, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1943; 001471
    - Topographic map. Groton, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31690) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1943; 002244
    - Topographic map. Groton, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1943; 002245
    - Topographic map. Woodhull, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1944; 001551
    - Topographic map. Cortland, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1944; 002238
    - Topographic map. Cortland, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1944; 002239
    - Topographic map. McGraw, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1944; 002251
    - Topographic map. McGraw, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 31680) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1944; 002252
    - Topographic map. Ashland, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001453
    - Topographic map. Durham, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001474
    - Topographic map. Fleischmanns, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001479
    - Topographic map. Franklin, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001480
    - Topographic map. Gilbertsville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001481
    - Topographic map. Gilboa, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001483
    - Topographic map. Guilford, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001484
    - Topographic map. Hensonville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001491
    - Topographic map. Lexington, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001498
    - Topographic map. Le Raysville, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001499
    - Topographic map. Livingstonville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001500
    - Topographic map. Margaretville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001505
    - Topographic map. Oneonta, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001512
    - Topographic map. Otego, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001514
    - Topographic map. Prattsville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001519
    - Topographic map. Smithville Flats, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001526
    - Topographic map. Treadwell, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001533
    - Topographic map. Unadilla, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001538
    - Topographic map. West Kill, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1945; 001546
    - Topographic map. Hobart, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1946; 001493
    - Topographic map. Roxbury, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 31680). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1946; 001522
    - Topographic map. Ithaca East, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1949; 001495
    - Topographic map. Ithaca West, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1949; 001496
    - Topographic map. Alpine, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001451
    - Topographic map. Burdett, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001462
    - Topographic map. Green, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001486
    - Topographic map. Marathon, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001503
    - Topographic map. Mecklenburg, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001506
    - Topographic map. Montour Falls, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001509
    - Topographic map. Reading Center, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001520
    - Topographic map. Richford, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001521
    - Topographic map. Troy, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001535
    - Topographic map. West Danby, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 001544
    - Topographic map. Reading Center, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 002264
    - Topographic map. Richford, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 002265
    - Topographic map. Richford, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 002266
    - Topographic map. West Danby, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1950; 002273
    - Topographic map. Brisben, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001461
    - Topographic map. Dryden, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001472
    - Topographic map. Harford, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001490
    - Topographic map. Lisle, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001501
    - Topographic map. Oxford, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001517
    - Topographic map. Speedsville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001527
    - Topographic map. Tyner, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001536
    - Topographic map. West Bainbridge, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001543
    - Topographic map. West Point, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001547
    - Topographic map. Willet, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001548
    - Topographic map. Willseyville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001549
    - Topographic map. Harford, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 002246
    - Topographic map. Lisle, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 002249
    - Topographic map. Lisle, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 002250
    - Topographic map. Speedsville, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 002268
    - Topographic map. Speedsville, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 002269
    - Topographic map. Gulf Summit, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001487
    - Topographic map. Windsor, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001550
    - Topographic map. Porterville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 002100
    - Topographic map. Afton, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 002101
    - Topographic map. Barton, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001454
    - Topographic map. Bath, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001455
    - Topographic map. Beaver Dams, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001456
    - Topographic map. Big Flats, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001457
    - Topographic map. Campbell, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001463
    - Topographic map. Corning, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001469
    - Topographic map. Hammondsport, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001488
    - Topographic map. Horseheads, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1953; 001494
    - Topographic map. Erin, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001478
    - Topographic map. Van Etten, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001539
    - Topographic map. New York State, Index of Topographic Maps (1: 1000000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001447
    - Topographic map. Apalachin, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001452
    - Topographic map. Candor, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001464
    - Topographic map. Maine, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001502
    - Topographic map. Newark Valley, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001511
    - Topographic map. Owego, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001516
    - Topographic map. Spencer, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001528
    - Topographic map. Owego, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 002259
    - Topographic map. Addison, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1969; 001943
    - Topographic map. New York State, SW-Central, Composite. U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 001448
    - Topographic map. Addison, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002230
    - Topographic map. Endicott, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002242
    - Topographic map. Lakewood, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002248
    - Topographic map. Mount Morris, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002253
    - Topographic map. Olean, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002257
    - Topographic map. Potter, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002262
    - Topographic map. Rathbone, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002263
    - Topographic map. Alfred, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002274
    - Topographic map. Whitney Point, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002275
    - Topographic map. Geneva South, NY 7.5 (1: 24000), 002290
    - map. Middlesex, NY 7.5 Quad (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002288
  - Pennsylvania. Topagraphic and geographic maps from Pennsylvania., 1959-1975; 001031
    - Topographic map. Elkland, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001475
    - Topographic map. Tioga, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001530
    - Topographic map. Troy, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1938; 001534
    - Topographic map. Sayre, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1948; 001523
    - Topographic map. Sayre, PA 15 Quad (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1948; 002267
    - Topographic map. Gillett, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001485
    - Topographic map. Millerton, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1954; 001508
    - Topographic map. Litchfield, PA 7.5 (1: 24000), 002291
- Miscellaneous, 1959-1975; Series III
  Scope and Contents
  Miscelanious Archives including notebooks and locality information.
  - Field Notebooks., 1959-1975; 001028
    - Notebook. Field Notebook and locality register: New York. 1957, 1958, 000063
  - Locality Information., 1959-1975; 001029
    - Locality information. Locality information for Devonian bivalves from the Moose River Group: Maine., 1962; 000355
    - Locality information. Papers & notes regarding Devonian Sonyea Group project including maps & locality register: New York. Maps obtained from NY State Museum, Albany (see notes). 1967, 1968, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1972, 000175
    - Locality information. Locality information, 000885